Hello, everyone. Welcome back. I'm going to be going into the skills exercise
for build applications with GitHub Copilot Agent Mode.
this is part of our GitHub Skills course catalog.
it is a self-service. all of the skills are self-service,
so any, any person can come into this,
organization and any of these repositories.
And run through these skills in their own,
user name or organization that they have within GitHub as well.
So I'm going to get started with kind of just a general read me
of this, as you can see here,
you know, we have a little welcome that walks through,
you know, about GitHub Copilot and what it can accomplish,
who this course is for, you know,
intermediate developers. What you learn,
what you'll build, any prerequisites,
and how long this should take about an hour.
And, that includes time for dealing with agent mode and
thinking and coming back into the conversation.
Both GitHub, Copilot Chat and Agent Mode in general are
very conversational. Obviously,
Agent Mode is able to make some assumptions based on context and walk through
things as well, but I'll get into that.
and then basically at this point, if you wanted to run this,
you could, right click. And then say open a new tab and then this
would allow you to create the repository under your username or organization
of your choice, and give it a description and then you can then start,
developing that.
the idea is that when you take this into your own repository,
once,
an action runs and it gets set up, This,
copy exercise would become gray, and then you would start the exercise,
and that's kind of what some of this dialogue here talks about,
so you can read through that as well.
and then,
we get into,
kind of the, the story,
this is just kind of showing a practical example of a fictitious,
high school called Mergenton High School, and
the Octofit Tracker Application Story.
four Mergington High School, where Paul Octo is,
has been a physical education teacher at Mergington High School for about eight years.
and despite his enthusiasm,
and creative approach to gym class, he's been increasingly concerned about his students,
you know,
that their physical activity is declined and many students admitted they're really actually,
exercise outside of PE class.
so really the objectives here for Paul is to make a fitness tracking app
fun and engaging, create positive peer pressure through friendly competition,
allow him to monitor student progress remotely,
and provide personalized guidance based on individual fitness levels.
and then this is where the birth of this app comes from,
and this just talks about the different user experience goals,
technical specifications,
and the current development status of where things are at,
and the next steps for Paul are with this basic infrastructure in place.
Paul's now focused on these items to start developing,
and then this workshop. You, the end user,
will set up a development environment using GitHub code spaces.
So, GitHub code spaces will have a full environment with a,
BS code IDE, as well as the ability to install packages and services,
and,
run, run them,
off of different ports as well, which we'll do as part of this app.
and then we'll use GitHub Copa,
Copa to accelerate the development across multiple technologies.
building key components for the OctoFit tracker app.
this was include,
user profiles, activity logging, tracking.
this talks just about the different models that are available.
so people can dig into that. And then we have some prompt engineering links
of how to do different techniques for prompt engineering,
as well as a link about agent mode,
the agent awakens blog,
that you can also,
if we were to bring this up here, they can read through this blog
directly,
about what, what that is. I'll close that now.
And then this talks about the React front end,
Python, Django back end, and a database MongoDB that we'll be using as part
of creating this app,
and some of the prerequisites.
the other thing that's, that's interesting, too,
is that,
trying to see the part about,
the other part I wanted to point out is that Paul is,
actively,
collaborating with the IT department and Jessica Cat,
is has been particularly impressed and pleased with OctoFit tracker
maintains the compliance with all the requirements specified.
And we have this file, this,
docs,
mergington,
techpolices.md that really Is a list of instructions
and guidance, forget of copilot agent mode,
as well as, if it was a human being, but in this case,
it's agent mode that's going through that dock and taking that,
to create the entire app for us.
We're just prompting it with different,
We're just giving you different prompts to guide through step-by-step to build this app
from the backend, the ground up,
the structure, all the way through, and we'll get into that now.
I also wanted to show to,
let's go to the pre,
the preparing. So, one of the things here in the preparing is that,
this is, you know, talks about the code space,
And this is where you would now,
right click and then open up this into a new,
and create a code space there. I happen to have mine up here.
So again, you have the same,
it's all the repositories checked out.
It's a fully functional development environment,
with VS code,
because this app is using multiple ports. I've opened those ports up and that's
already built in as part of the code space.
and this again is the read me for the story.
and then if I was going to then start this,
exercise I'd come back here,
my code space has been created. And at that point,
I've started to walk through,
you know, building this app. This just talks about also your repository in your,
in your,
you know, the full repo name that you've created that you've cloned this template
from. And,
you can create a branch, for example,
I get up copilot application,
and you can do things like that,
as well as part of this, but,
right now we'll dive into,
the bill, this is really the meat of it. So we have about,
really five or four main steps.
The first one's just a preparation. This gets into,
the application set up the directory structure,
the Python requirements, the Django project app,
and MongoDB,
So by just giving it this prompt,
we can start this process, and I'll kind of show an example of that.
So what they usually would do is they would, you know,
obviously in their code space, they could open up,
all of the same files.
I'm going to, we're going to ask them to open up this file as
well as our,
our story and our tech specs for Mergington High School.
and we're going to keep those open. I'll probably move this over here just
so it's the primary thing.
and now this is our co-pilot chat window where we're going to hit co-pilot
edits. And here we're going to select agent.
We're going to stay with the GPT4O model.
and
let me just move,
my video out of my video over here.
So I'm out of the way a bit.
and then you can see what's going on here a little bit better.
so then we would take this first prompt here,
we'll open this up, we'll, we'll copy this,
and we're going to do is we're going to say add context.
This pop-up will happen. It'll happen a couple times and you just click allow,
and we're going to say open editor. So then what that means is everything
that's open right now and our editor up here is what the context that
GitHub co-pilot.
agent mode is going to use,
for, for this effort. And then I'm going to paste this and we're going
to see what,
the magic that agent mode already has as part of it.
it's going to go through now. And it's going to read.
It's going to say, oh, you need to make this directory to create the
structure.
so it's going to open up a new terminal window to do that.
it's going to then say, okay, I need this requirements.
And it's going to touch this file to create the file.
And as you can see on the left side here, we're starting to create
the application. And here it's already created our requirements for the Python packages
that need to be installed. I'm going to keep that file because I want
to save it. We'll end up checking all these in as a user.
They'll also be checking these in. And then we can continue.
again, one of those allow block windows will open up and just hit allow.
and that's really the first,
prompt. Obviously I'm, I'm looking, I'm not looking at this in the nice pretty
markdown. This is the raw markdown file,
but
same, same thing that they would see,
the nice pretty version, or they can look at this too either way.
So at this point, we've now installed all of the Python packages that we
need for the back end to start to develop our app.
It is telling us like, do we want to set up the project?
We could say yes there,
I've designed this so that we are really kind of doing this step by
step to show the end user,
what they're building. So then we would copy this prompt and then we would
say, okay, now I'll create the,
the back end,
set up any additional configuration for the Django project app.
And we'll do that here. Now we created the app.
We are also going to do,
something that with,
Django, it does this, has this manager,
Python script that allows for,
making migrations and then, and migrating so we should see something that checks everything
out for us and everything looks good.
And at this point, we're very happy and we could actually run the server
if we wanted to. And just like that,
we have already the Django server up and running.
In our environment that is set to go obviously nothing's been set up for
our specific app, but the Django,
stack has been set up for us.
I'm going to close that, come back here,
and then we can go to,
installing. I'm not going to walk through every single step here,
but you get the idea at this point, we would install the database,
and we would do those things. So,
if you were to hop around to number three,
For example, then what we would do is start creating,
filling in the Django project of all of the files we need for URLs,
views, model serializers, settings,
and the admin files, any tests as well,
and then we would,
prompt to create the database structure,
the MongoDB database structure here with this prompt and this activity.
Then we would edit the,
Octofit tracker,
Django files here for each one of those,
that we already talked about in the last activity.
And then this last step here is last activity in this step is to
actually populate the database with some test data that we get,
you know, made up,
and then we're going to create this Python populate DB script that will automatically,
populate that database for us. And then once that's done,
Then what we can do is we can really,
set up the rest API framework,
for with, with the, with the Django,
rest framework.
when it comes set up initially, it's going to have local host as URL
and that really is not going to do anything for us.
So what these steps do is it actually helps replace with our code space.
So if I was to go,
back to my code space, this would be the name that I would replace.
in that step here at the top, you can see that,
and
sorry, go, yep.
we would replace that with our specific name so we would kind of take
from the bracket here and put the,
the name of our code space and then that would automatically replace
in the URLs and views, everything that's necessary so that then we have the
right end points and then,
we could get all of the information out of the database from that point
on. The last piece of this right now,
is to set up the front end,
react framework,
so that's what, oops,
in the wrong one. It would set up the React framework,
so we would, we would set up these different,
components as well as update the app and indexes of the React framework.
and with this we would have activities, the leaderboard team users and,
and workout, and that should also get the information back from what's in the
database today.
and these was just some other things, other, other activities of updating that front
end components and then to verify them and check the output at the very
end.
I plan to also add one more step,
maybe for generating some tests so people can see that as well to test
the app.
but overall this is pretty complete that we could create a full stack app
at this point if we wanted to.
so I hope this was informative.
I may do follow up videos as we kind of finalize the skill.
It's still kind of in a draft form,
but most of the details and it working is there.
I just wanted to,
get it out there before it's finalized and we're all complete.
just because there's some other iterations I'd like to do on peer reviews and
having,
having some of the documentation may be updated,
as well. We can use Copilot as a peer reviewer.
Or so I also might run it through co-pilot to review it before we
check everything in,
and finalize it. But
thank you for the time. I hope this was useful, and we'll see you
again soon.