Welcome to build applications with co-pilot agent mode.
We're in the continuous co-pilot org, and now we'll copy the exercise to our
GitHub handle, or an organization of our chosen.
As you can see, I'm going to use my GitHub handle,
and I'll add an additional note to the description,
and then once that is complete,
I'll be ready to create the repository.
This will just take a moment, and the repository will come up.
It will look identical to what we just saw,
but instead, if we refresh an action is running in the background,
that will turn copy exercise, gray,
and start exercise, green,
which allows us to begin. Now
we'll right click on open in GitHub code spaces,
and we'll say create new code space.
This is a fully featured development environment that has all
the extensions we need, including GitHub Copilot and Copilot Chat.
It'll take a moment for the configuration and environment to come up.
And as you can see, our extensions are installing by that blue time
circle on the left. Now
GitHub Copilot Chat is installed and we can begin chatting.
Let's go to the first prompt, copy it,
and then we'll hit Command-I or Control-I if you're on Windows.
Paste that in and ask Copilot to help us with the command
to create a branch. We'll now also
ask Copilot and prompt it to create a specific branch called
BuildOctoFitApp.
Once that's complete, we can run that command,
and if we look here, we have the new branch created.
Now, we can now proceed to the next step.
We'll open some files to get ready. We're
going to open up a readme that has all of the information about another
repository app that we're modeling for this app.
So we'll open those files, so this way Copilot Chat Agent Mode can use
that as references and content to look at.
We'll copy the first prompt and make sure we're in Agent Mode from the
drop down in the chat window. We'll paste the prompt and
we'll wait for the return and response.
So GitHub Copilot has identified that we want to make the structure for this
application OctoFid tracker app.
We also want to create a virtual environment as well.
This allows us to write everything and develop everything in Python in
a virtual environment instead of installing it directly in the code space.
You'll also now create our requirements.txt which has all of the modules
and libraries that will need to create
this app and install Our Jane go back end that we'll show later.
All these requirements will take a moment to install,
but what's great about this is that Copilot Agent Mode has not
only identified the requirements based on the reference app that we're using from
another repository, but it's generating all of the requirements in a
text but we can then check in and use later on.
We'll also keep that file, and now we'll ask Copilot Chat
To create the backend.
This Django backend will be where we set up our project and set up
our REST API so that the front end can talk to it.
Once it's done, we'll run some system commands related to Django about migrating
the database.
As you can see, everything is come back okay,
and we're ready to proceed to the next step. Or say the next activity.
At this point, we're also going to install a database,
so we'll install MongoDB and Copilot will take the
reference command of installing MongoDB and know how to do that and return that
and we can run that command. Now we're installing MongoDB
and this will just take a moment as it's updating all of the packages
on the in the code space. And it's also then installing the MongoDB
package as well. Now if we go to the next prompt,
we want to start the MongoDB service and make sure that it's running.
Now we're ready to go to step three. Let's see the
first activity which is creating and populating the database.
I should say setting up the structure for the database.
So this will create all of the collections that we want with all of
the components, leaderboard,
activities, users, team, and
also workouts. Uh, we'll also make sure that it's actually Korean
created and you can see all of the collections that we have here.
Now we also want to update some of the files that are going to
set up the Django app. And
this includes views, serializers,
URLs, models, just to name a few.
So what co-pilot agent mode's doing now is it's going through identifying
where it needs to create these files, the names of the files,
and also the contents of them.
And we'll be asked to keep these files as they're created Or we
can also decide to undo them. In this case, we are going to keep
them because we trust that copilot agent mode is creating these in the right
manner and the right contents are inside.
As all of these pop-up will just press keep,
you can do this in the chat panel directly or you can do it
file by file in the editor and the inline editor in the middle.
It's also going to create an admin.py and a test.py for us as well.
Yep, we're going to keep all these files.
So now we have the database created all
of the structure for the Django project that
will be our backend that talks to the database.
And now we want to write a script that will populate the database from
the Django backend. First we'll do another migrate.
Just to make sure everything is clean and there are no issues there.
As you can see also in the lower right, um,
this is running. We could pause or stop in that chat window.
Um, but obviously we want to keep the commands coming.
It makes it convenient that agent mode can identify what needs to run and
let us run those commands.
Now we'll write a script to populate the database.
So, wrote a script called populate underscore db.py,
and now we'll do another migrate.
The next thing it should do is now run the populate to put all
the contents we want and the sample data in the database.
So, we're successful there. We'll move on to step four.
We've populated the database. And now we want to create the rest API endpoints.
We want to use the actual name of our code space,
which you can see in the, uh,
top title bar that I'm highlighting right now.
And I'm only taking up to the point where it gets to,
uh, dash, or sorry,
dot, github.dev. And
I'm going to replace this in the prompt where it says replace this
with your code space. Name in two places.
And what this will do is it will update in the views.py,
the actual code space endpoint with the port 8000,
that's for the Django backend. Since that will be set up,
we can then talk directly to those endpoints instead of trying to bring
it up with local hosts, which will not work in the browser.
So what Copilot will do is it will look for what it needs to
change.
And as you can see, it's swapped out the name localhost for
the name of our code space and the port,
um, and the extension GitHub dev.
We're not going to run the server from there.
We're going to follow the instructions here and we have some preloaded Uh,
launch.json in the vs.bsco directory that we can then run the app.
We'll make the port public.
We'll see that it's running. You can make it public
when the when it pops up or you can open the browser.
In this case, I went into the port directly here on this option and
I made it public. I actually made Uh,
both ports 3,000 and 8,000 public.
Because that will be for the React front end. As you can see,
we have all the data that, the sample data that was populated by PopulateDB.
We have the endpoints where we can look at the API,
we can get all of that information, we can also post back to it
as well. So here is the front end,
uh, made up of the React framework, some,
uh, bootstrap and the React,
uh, DOM router. Uh,
and some other Node.js components. Uh,
we created these files on all the components.
Now we want to actually format into more tables and
for each component and make it look nice and neat.
Um, you'll see what it looks like now before.
We actually implement that. So while this is working,
We're actually updating all of the component files,
all the JavaScript files for each component, so for activities,
teams, users, leaderboard,
workouts, um,
and as you can see, those are all the components, all the JavaScript files
right there on the left side.
Now we'll look at it before it's updated and see how it's just like
stacked links. Not very pretty,
it's got the main React JS, uh,
default image. That's the rest API. Um,
so we noticed too by clicking there,
it wasn't actually going to any of the data. So we really have to
make these ports public. Um, I'm gonna make both the Java,
uh, sorry, the React, uh,
front end, 3,000 and the,
um, Django back end, 8,000 port public.
And now if we click it, let's do refresh,
yeah. And actually while we were going to click that,
um, all of the updates to our,
uh, components were, were done. So now we can see everything as,
um, a nice little format,
but you see it hasn't propagated through all of the files yet.
So if we go back, you can see that it's still editing all of
these component JavaScript files for each of our,
uh, error, you know,
all of the, um, whether it's workouts, activities,
leaderboard teams and users. Now if we look,
it's starting to need it up across the board and be consistent with all
of the, um, the tables. Our API still works.
Have all the data there just like we're looking there.
So now we can start to add some color or some background and do
other things to beautify this app that we've created.
This kind of shows where we're headed. We can actually let users in the
course kind of, uh, put their own,
uh, prompts in agent mode of things that they may want to change the
app to look like. Maybe you want to add features. Um,
and that's the subsequent, um, exercise activities as
we go. Um, so I'm going to make some changes here,
but you guys get to just, uh, thank you.
I hope this was helpful for training the trainer for our,
um, our AI skills.