Hi, my name is Ari LiVigni. Welcome to Microsoft AI SkillsFest,
and this is the specific, train-the-trainer for build applications
with GitHub Copilot Agent Mode. we'll do a title slide here,
a brief introduction of myself, and my credentials,
and what team I'm with, and some of my hobbies,
and things that I do outside of work time.
and then we'll tag folks about the Guinness Book of World Records,
the QR code, and how they can also,
interact with our live moderators in chat as well.
the agenda for this,
is about five points. We'll do an introduction of GitHub Copilot Agent Mode,
the learning objectives that users will achieve,
in this skills course. Explore the power of GitHub Copilot Agent Mode.
some of the background on the skill and kind of the setting of it,
and,
what we'll be covering. And then we'll get right into,
building an application directly,
with Agent Mode, and we're going to call it OctoFit Tracker.
the slides. Here's the brief introduction.
So,
you know, this is really about experiencing the next evolution of AI-assisted coding
with GitHub Copilot Agent Mode, an autonomous peer programmer capable of performing
multi-step coding tasks as you, as,
as your command, at your command. It analyzes your code base,
reads relevant files, proposes file edits,
and runs termination. and tests,
Agent Mode iterates on its own code. So if it finds an error in
some of the code it's written or a command,
it recognizes those errors and then will fix them automatically.
it is available as a preview as of now,
as of March 17th.
and it's in the VS Code Insiders for users currently.
the learning objectives will be understanding how to develop with the VS Code IDE
in a GitHub code space,
prompt,
GitHub Copilot Agent Mode to create an application,
leverage,
internal, or I should say, leverage documentation files that are in the repository,
in the GitHub repository to instruct GitHub Copilot Agent Mode.
And GitHub Copilot Agent Mode iterates over the code base,
Thank That's in the repository, it'll fix errors,
refactor code, and also help develop new features.
kind of the key points in exploring GitHub Copilot Agent Mode is,
is its features of autonomous operation.
Copilot Agent Mode operates in a more autonomous and dynamic manner to achieve the
desired outcome. It determines the relevant context and files to execute.
It can edit autonomously without explicit user specification.
multi-step tasks, it can perform multi-step coding tasks,
such as creating apps from scratch, performing refactorings across multiple files,
and writing and running tests.
we'll be running through all of this during the exercise in the skills course.
tools for task completion. Agent Mode uses a set of tools to perform specific
tasks. Like editing files and running terminal commands.
These tools can run in parallel. Examples include listing files,
reading file contents, running terminal commands,
and getting terminal output.
code changes and terminal commands, Compilot will suggest both code changes and terminal
commands to complete the task. It might compile a code instead of install packages.
And run tests,
iteration and self-healing, as I talked about earlier.
Agent mode iterates independently to achieve the desired outcome,
fixing issues as they come up.
It monitors the correctness of code edits and terminal command
output and iterates to remediate issues.
It can detect issues and problems in code edits.
And terminal commands and perform additional actions to resolve them.
It, it also analyzes runtime errors with self-healing capabilities.
it is user control and review. You can keep files or dispose of them.
and it will request confirmation or ask questions.
So it's very conversational back and forth as is co-pilot chat originally.
and you can also modify proposed terms. Terminal commands before running them,
context management, while autonomous.
You can still explicitly reference context with the pound file using
drag and drop of certain files.
you can also use code,
the hash code bit code base. It's a chat,
a chat,
variable,
in your prompt to let co-pilot find the right files automatically.
I'll see you So, requires enabling,
the GitHub co-pilot chat code search enabled preview in the preview setting.
You can undo and redo,
you can interrupt requests,
and there are the limitations we'll review also as agent mode is currently in
a preview and available in VS Code or VS Code Insiders.
So, it has not G, G8 yet,
and there definitely is,
it's, it's experimental, and we're you.
Using that to collect feedback from users and early adopters.
It might take longer to get a response due to multiple steps.
It can be more non-deterministic than edit mode.
It may also quickly you, use up your free co-pilot quota as it,
sends multiple requests per prompt. Agent mode is not available for working with notebooks,
in VS Code.
and then we will,
at that point, go to the next slide.
So this kind of talks about more of the skill background,
and in the next video, I'll get into really walking through the skill,
the skill course that we have in github.com,
and it's part of our,
our skill course catalog. But the background on this skill is that we're,
we're developing a fictitious app,
at Mergington High School.
the characters are Paul Octo, who is a gym teacher,
and is,
working with someone in IT, Jessica Cat,
to create a,
an app to keep,
students more active. So students rarely exercise outside of the required PE class.
So,
we needed, he needed an app to create an email.
to create,
activities to be more fun and engaging, to keep,
students on track for their fitness goals.
the solution, therefore, is developing this OctoFit Tracker app,
a social fitness tracking application built with GitHub Copilot Agent Mode,
and it's compliant with the school policy. So, this Mergington Tech Dollars,
Tech Policies,
Markdown 5, is what's used to really generate a lot of,
what Copilot Agent Mode uses to create its code,
and its terminal commands, and give us direction on continuously developing
the,
backend, the database, and the frontend React,
frontend of the app.
the key features is that we'll have user profiles and activity logs,
team competitions,
and a leaderboard,
personalized,
workout suggestions,
progress tracking dashboard,
and so your task as the,
as, as the person taking this course and being part of our SkillsFest challenge
is to follow Paul's journey using GitHub Codespaces,
learn to leverage GitHub Copilot Agent Mode,
and build a similar application with the help of GitHub,
GitHub Copilot Agent Mode. And that kind of summarizes,
that. And then this is a link to the repository that we'll have,
and they can QR code scan this, or they can go to the short
link to build the app,
and as, sorry, get to the skills course and start developing it in their
own,
workspace.
then we'll have just a congratulations. This is all standard as part of the
whole Skills Fest and the Day Zero,
Guinness Book,
slides. So we're just putting this in our slide deck as well.
and thank you for attending. And that's the end of the deck.
So I'm going to stop the video there,
and then we'll dive into the next video,
the actual skills course that we're going to use.